<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">

    <string name="cptPolskyTabulky">Pigpen &amp; Grid Ciphers</string>
    <string name="cptTabulky">Pigpen &amp; Grid Ciphers</string>
    <string name="tTDTab">Cipher grid:</string>
    <string name="tTDVar">Variant:</string>
    <string name="tTDVstup">Visual input:</string>
    <string name="tTDSour">Coordinate input:</string>

    <string name="tTDErrMobilVar">Unavailable for this grid.</string>

    <string name="tTDCtvBifidXY">Bifid cipher, XY</string>
    <string name="tTDCtvBifidYX">Bifid cipher, YX</string>
	
	
<string name="tHelpTabulky"><![CDATA[
<h1>Pigpen &amp; Grid Ciphers</h1>

<p>This component helps solving pigpen ciphers (also known as masonic or Rosicrucian ciphers),
Polybius square, and multi-tap encoding by displaying the appropriate grid as an interactive
widget. Input once entered can also be re-translated in several variants, e.g., rotations
of the grid, possibly saving a number of unsuccessful attempts. The bifid and trifid ciphers,
closely related to grid ciphers, can also be found here.</p>


<h3>Basic usage</h3>

<p>Use the two menus in the top to select the overall kind of cipher and one of its usual
variants. The app will draw the cipher grid annotated by letters at the appropriate positions.
These can be read directly or stored in the <i>Plaintext</i> field by clicking at them. This
is not only useful to for easy reading of the decoded message as a whole but also used as
input when the <i>Variants</i> tab is open.</p>


<h5>3×3 + 2×2 layout</h5>

<p>This is the original masonic cipher. Each letter is encoded to a partial frame of a square,
either straight or tilted by 45 degrees, and either empty or with a dot inside it. All the 26
combinations can be found in the screen. Their meaning in the alphabet depends on the order
in which the symbols are assigned. This can be controlled using the <i>Variant</i> menu.</p>

<p>If <i>Variants</i> are requested for this layout, the same input is reinterpreted with
different assignments of symbols to letters, with a rotation applied on the symbols, in mirror
image, and/or with the presence of dots reversed.</p>


<h5>3×3×3 layout</h5>

<p>This is an alternative layout of the pigpen cipher without the slanted boxes, but with up
to 2 dots inside the frame. In another variant there is exactly one dot in each frame but differing
in position: aligned to the left, right, or centered. The displayed grid adapts to the selected
layout and displays all the possible combinations in an intuitive manner.</p>

<p>As there are effectively three coordinates assuming values 1, 2, 3, these can also be entered
numerically using the buttons at the bottom of the screen. Only each complete triple is processed.</p>

<p>The <i>Variants</i> provided for this cipher comprise swapping the order of the coordinates,
e.g., row number for column number, and mirror reversal of the axes. The <b>trifid</b> cipher
decoding can also be reached through <i>3×3×3</i> layout variants.</p>


<h5>Polybius square</h5>

<p>Polybius (5×5) square-based ciphers can be found either referring directly to the positions within
the square, or pairs of coordinates of 1 through 5. For this reason the letters can be located in
the square directly or their coordinates entered by the buttons along the bottom of the screen.
As the square allows for only 25 positions, one letter must be taken out of the alphabet. It is
possible to choose J (in which case it becomes represented by I), K (becomes one with C in so-called
<i>tap code</i>), Q, or X. Note that this temporary setting does not depend on the global alphabet
alterations nor does it affect them.</p>

<p>The <i>Variants</i> available for the Polybius square comprise rotations and mirror reflections
of the whole square, as well as the <b>bifid</b> cipher.</p>


<h5>Multi-tap</h5>

<p>A multi-tap encoding, inspired by the 9-key cell phone keypads, represents each letter by a digit
identifying the key and the number of times it is pressed. The labels on the keys displayed by the
widget can be read by sight or the keys can be pressed as in an actual multi-tap.</p>

<p>There are no <i>Variants</i> for this layout as the unused \"1\" key and the four possible letters
on both \"7\" and \"9\" make the correct orientation unambiguous.</p>


<h3>Encryption</h3>

<p>The <i>Encrypt</i> tab gives the possibility to encrypt plaintext by the enlisted methods. The details
depend on the current layout:</p>

<p><b>3×3×3 layout</b>: graphical representation (white on black, in exported bitmaps black on white),
coordinates in the row–column–dot position (L–C–R dot variant) or grid–row–column (0/1/2 dots variant)
order and trifid cipher using two possible orderings: row–column–dot and column–row–dot (L–C–R) or
grid–row–column and grid–column–row (0/1/2).</p>

<p><b>3×3 + 2×2 layout</b>: graphical and textual representation. In the latter, the digits 1 to 9 denote
the position of the square if upright (ordered like in a numpad with 1 in the upper left corner), letters
A through D label the four possible tilted squares (in the order they are assigned in the cipher) and
an optional star appended to the code marks the presence of a dot.</p> 
 
<p><b>Polybius square</b>: graphical representations in two forms, with the marked square inside the 5×5
working field or inside or on the outer margin of a 3×3 square. The position of the mark is the same in
both variants, only the referential shape differs. Other options are a textual representation, encoding
every letter into a pair of coordinates 1 through 5, and the bifid cipher using both row–column and
column–row orderings in its calculation.</p>

<p><b>Multi-tap</b>: a direct multi-tap representation, showing the actual repetitions of the buttons,
or pairs of digits composed of button label and repetition count.</p>


<h3>Preferences</h3>

<p>The Preferences screen allows to customize whether a visual feedback is shown when the individual
letters in the grids are selected using a finger. This allows to avoid hitting nearby letters by mistake
on small displays where they are closely stacked. This feature is useless in tablets or when using
a stylus so it can be turned off to avoid distraction.</p>


<h3>Tips and tricks</h3>

<p>The app remembers the locations of the individual characters (or their coordinates) in the grids at
the moment they were entered. When a different variant of the layout is selected at a later point,
the <i>Plaintext</i> field is recomputed to reflect the new layout.</p>

<p><i>NB</i>, however, that for the same reason, the data can not be brought to a different grid type
and the plaintext is cleared when a different type of the cipher is selected.</p>
]]></string>


    <string-array name="saTDTabulky">
        <item>3×3+2×2 layout</item>
        <item>3×3×3 layout</item>
        <item>Polybius square</item>
        <item>Multi-tap</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTDTabulky">
        <item>@id/idTDMPolsky</item>
        <item>@id/idTDVPolsky</item>
        <item>@id/idTDCtverec</item>
        <item>@id/idTDMobil</item>
    </array>


    <string-array name="saTDVPVar">
        <item>L–C–R dot</item>
        <item tools:ignore="TypographyFractions">0/1/2 dots</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTDVPVar">
        <item>@id/idTDVPKlas</item>
        <item>@id/idTDVPAlt</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTDVPABCVar">
        <item/>
        <item/>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="saTDMPVar">
        <item>9 – • – 4</item>
        <item>9 – 4 – •</item>
        <item>• – 9 – 4</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTDMPVar">
        <item>@id/idTDMP9T4</item>
        <item>@id/idTDMP94T</item>
        <item>@id/idTDMPT94</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTDMPABCVar">
        <item/>
        <item/>
        <item/>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="saTDCtvVar">
        <item>– J (Polybius)</item>
        <item>– K (Tap code)</item>
        <item>– Q</item>
        <item>– X</item>
        <!--item>6×6 with digits</item-->
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saTDCtvABCVar">
        <item>J:5</item>
        <item>K:5</item>
        <item>Q:5</item>
        <item>X:5</item>
        <!--item>dig:6</item-->
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="saTVVPGroups">
        <item>Permutations</item>
        <item>Permutations and reflections</item>
        <item>Trifid cipher</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTVVPGroups">
        <item>@id/idTVVProt</item>
        <item>@id/idTVVProtzrc</item>
        <item>@id/idTVVPtrifid</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTVVPABCVar">
        <item/>
        <item/>
        <item/>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="saTVVPPerm" translatable="false">
        <item>YXZ</item>
        <item>XYZ</item>
        <item>ZXY</item>
        <item>ZYX</item>
        <item>YZX</item>
        <item>XZY</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saTVVPRefl" translatable="false">
        <item>rY</item>
        <item>rX</item>
        <item>rZ</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saTVVPAltPerm" translatable="false">
        <item>ZYX</item>
        <item>YZX</item>
        <item>XYZ</item>
        <item>XZY</item>
        <item>ZXY</item>
        <item>YXZ</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saTVVPAltRefl" translatable="false">
        <item>rZ</item>
        <item>rY</item>
        <item>rX</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="saTCVPItems">
        <item>Graphical representation</item>
        <item>Coordinates (YXZ)</item>
        <item>Trifid cipher (YXZ)</item>
        <item>Trifid cipher (XYZ)</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTCVPItems">
        <item>@id/idTCPrimo</item>
        <item>@id/idTCSour</item>
        <item>@id/idTCVPTrifid931</item>
        <item>@id/idTCVPTrifid391</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTCVPAltItems">
        <item>Graphical representation</item>
        <item>Coordinates (ZYX)</item>
        <item>Trifid cipher (ZYX)</item>
        <item>Trifid cipher (ZXY)</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTCVPAltItems">
        <item>@id/idTCPrimo</item>
        <item>@id/idTCSour</item>
        <item>@id/idTCVPTrifid931</item>
        <item>@id/idTCVPTrifid913</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTCMPItems">
        <item>Graphical representation</item>
        <item>Textual representation</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTCMPItems">
        <item>@id/idTCPrimo</item>
        <item>@id/idTCSour</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTCCtvItems">
        <item>5×5</item>
        <item>3×3 + margin</item>
        <item>Coordinates (YX)</item>
        <item>Bifid cipher (YX)</item>
        <item>Bifid cipher (XY)</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTCCtvItems">
        <item>@id/idTCCtv5x5</item>
        <item>@id/idTCCtv3x3</item>
        <item>@id/idTCSour</item>
        <item>@id/idTCCtvBifidYX</item>
        <item>@id/idTCCtvBifidXY</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="saTCMobilItems">
        <item>Multi-tap</item>
        <item>Key + repetitions</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTCMobilItems">
        <item>@id/idTCMobilMulti</item>
        <item>@id/idTCMobilPocet</item>
    </array>
</resources>
