<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="cptSemafor">Semaphore</string>
    <string name="tSmDTitul">Mark two directions:</string>
    <string name="tSmDNavrhy">Suggestions:</string>

    <string name="patSmVPosun" translatable="false">%1$s+ %2$d (– %3$d)</string>
    <string name="tSmVInv">inv </string>
	
	
<string name="tHelpSemafor"><![CDATA[
<h1>Semaphore</h1>

<p>This components helps decode or encode in the Flag semaphore telegraphy system.</p>


<h3>Basic usage</h3>

<p>Any semaphore character is represented by the position of a pair of flags, each in one of eight
possible directions. These eight directions correspond to the eight highlighted areas of screen.
A pair can be entered by tapping two appropriate circular marks, simultaneously using two fingers,
or in a swipe.</p>

<p>As long as just one circle has been highlighted, all the characters having one of their flags
in that direction are listed as suggestions. Aside from tapping the second circle, a character
can be selected from these suggestions.</p>  


<h3>Variants</h3>

<p>If the decoded string makes little sense, it has been perhaps obfuscated by the author of the
puzzle by turning or reflecting the semaphore signs (this may also be the result of representing
the directions by numbers in incompatible ways as there is no standard numbering). For these
situations, <i>Semaphore</i> offers the <i>Variants</i> tab, where the previously entered input
is reconsidered in a rotated and/or mirrored coordinate system. All possible transformations of
this kind are listed.</p>

<p><i>NB</i> that the occurrence of the number sign (see below) may result in different lengths
of the variants.</p>


<h3>Encryption</h3>

<p>The <i>Encrypt</i> tab can be used to encode an input string into the semaphore alphabet.
The output can be obtained in a graphical or numeric representation. The former can be exported
as a PNG file (in black on white background), the latter in plain text, which might be more
useful if further processed. In the numeric representation, each character is converted to
a pair of digits in the range 1 through 8 where the numbering is chosen so that A, B, C, …, G
correspond to 12, 13, 14, …, 18.</p>


<h3>Preferences</h3>

<p>By default the component is set up to recognize the 26 English letters and a number sign.
This leaves only one unassigned combination. The number sign switches the interpretation of the
first 11 combinations (originally letters A through K) to digits 1–9 and 0 (K), J becoming the
\"character sign\" which reverses the assignments to normal. The number sign can be disabled
in the preferences so that it stays unrecognized and the switching to numeric mode never occurs.</p>


<h3>Tips and tricks</h3>

<p>If the numeric mode is entered by mistake and you wish to exit it promptly instead of
remembering the character sign, use <i>BackSpace</i>.</p>
]]></string>


    <string-array name="saSmRGroups">
        <item>Letters</item>
        <item>Digits</item>
        <item>Control</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaSmRGroups">
        <item>@array/saSmDPismena</item>
        <item>@array/saSmDCislice</item>
        <item>@array/saSmDPrefixy</item>
    </array>


    <string-array name="saSmDPismena">
        <item>3:A</item>
        <item>5:B</item>
        <item>9:C</item>
        <item>17:D</item>
        <item>33:E</item>
        <item>65:F</item>
        <item>129:G</item>
        <item>6:H</item>
        <item>10:I</item>
        <item>80:J</item>
        <item>18:K</item>
        <item>34:L</item>
        <item>66:M</item>
        <item>130:N</item>
        <item>12:O</item>
        <item>20:P</item>
        <item>36:Q</item>
        <item>68:R</item>
        <item>132:S</item>
        <item>24:T</item>
        <item>40:U</item>
        <item>144:V</item>
        <item>96:W</item>
        <item>160:X</item>
        <item>72:Y</item>
        <item>192:Z</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saSmDCislice">
        <item>3:1</item>
        <item>5:2</item>
        <item>9:3</item>
        <item>17:4</item>
        <item>33:5</item>
        <item>65:6</item>
        <item>129:7</item>
        <item>6:8</item>
        <item>10:9</item>
        <item>18:0</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saSmDPrefixy">
        <item>48:digits:</item>
        <item>80:letters:</item>
        <item>136:cancel:</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="saSCItems">
        <item>Graphical representation</item>
        <item>Pairs of 1–8 (1 = down, then CW)</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaSCItems">
        <item>@id/idSCPrimo</item>
        <item>@id/idSCDvoj</item>
    </array>

</resources>
