<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="cptTrans">Transposition Ciphers</string>
    <string name="tTTitle">Ciphertext:</string>
    <string name="tTTvar">Shape:</string>
    <string name="tTTab">Use up to three fingers to manipulate:</string>
    <string name="tTClearSol">Clear plaintext</string>
    <string name="tTClearTrf">Clear transform</string>

    <string name="tTRevX" translatable="false"><b>↔</b></string>
    <string name="tTRevY" translatable="false"><b>↕</b></string>
    <string name="tTRevDiag" translatable="false"><b>X↔Y</b></string>

    <string-array name="saTTvary">
        <item>None</item>
        <item>Rectangle</item>
        <item>Triangle (vertex first)</item>
        <item>Triangle (base first)</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaTTvary">
        <item>@id/idTNic</item>
        <item>@id/idTObdelnik</item>
        <item>@id/idTTrojuhelnik</item>
        <item>@id/idTRTrojuhelnik</item>
    </array>
	
	
<string name="tHelpTrans"><![CDATA[
<h1>Transposition Ciphers</h1>

<p>This component helps deciphering or designing transposition ciphers, i.e., those in which
the letters forming the ciphertext only need to be read in a different order.</p>


<h3>Basic usage</h3>

<p>Enter the ciphertext in the equally labeled field; if intending to <i>create</i> a transposition cipher,
put the plaintext there. Select from the menu how the letters should initially be laid out on the
screen. The options are no formatting (the app only allows to hand-pick the letters in any order
and displays which ones have already been used) or aligning the letters in a rectangle or a triangle.
Finally, confirm your input using the Enter key or the arrow-shaped button.</p>

<p>Upon entering, the input is split into single letters and displayed in the <i>Working area</i>.
<i>NB</i> that the parsing may depend on the preferences (see below). Depending on the layout selected
in the <i>Shape</i> field, this can be further processed for an easier reading. In the case of unformatted
display, the font size can be changed using pinch zoom for a more comfortable addressing of single
letters. For all the other layouts, the contents of the working surface can be <i>moved</i> (using
single finger touch and drag), <i>zoomed and/or rotated</i> (using two fingers) and even <i>deformed</i>
(dragging three points at a time).</p>

<p>If <i>Rectangle</i> is chosen as the shape, you can further change the required count of columns
or rows. To do so, touch a point <i>beyond the edge</i> of the current rectangle and hold until a borderline
appears around the text. Moving your finger closer to or farther from the centre of the rectangle without
interrupting the contact, you can adjust the column count (if the motion started to the left or right
of the rectangle) or the row count (if it was initiated above or below the rectangle). The borderline will
continually reflect these changes and the actual contents will be realigned when the resizing is done.</p>

<p><i>NB</i> that if the letter count is not a multiple of the given column or row count, i.e.,
unless the input fills the rectangle evenly, the layout will be slightly different depending on
whether an alignment in a fixed number of columns or rows was requested. In the former case, the
rectangle is filled by rows, when reaching the end of one row, a new one starts. In the latter,
the app also uses the letters left to right, top to bottom, but tries to fill the rows as evenly
as possible, perhaps leaving more than just the last one row shorter than the others.</p> 

<p>Some common actions in the working area have shortcuts in its lower right corner: reverting
the view to its original size, rotation and position, horizontal, vertical mirror image and a
matrix-like transposition along a diagonal axis.</p> 

<p>Manipulate the working area so that the letters that belong in a row get next to one another.
After you reach a state in which the plaintext stands out, you can either read it already or use the
app to collect the letters one by one in the correct order. Any letter clicked in the working area
appears in the <i>Plaintext</i> field and is drawn in green from then on to distinguish it as already
used. Other letters of the same kind get temporarily drawn in yellow. This is very useful when solving
certain kinds of graphical ciphers which rely on the correct realignment of the letters.</p>

<p>It is not yet possible to delete letters picked by mistake. The <i>BackSpace</i> button clears
the whole plaintext (redrawing all letters in the working surface in white) so you can start anew.
All the geometric transformations remain. To revert them as well, use the <i>Clear all</i> action
button / menu item.</p>


<h3>Example</h3>

<p>Consider a transposition cipher in which you find that every third letter is supposed to be read.
You can use the <i>Transposition ciphers</i> tool as follows: enter the whole ciphertext as it is
and choose a rectangle for shape. By default, the letters are aligned into 8 columns. We only want
3 columns, so that every third letter starts a new row and thus they can be read vertically. To
change column count, touch and hold your finger beyond the left or right edge of the current rectangle
(making it smaller using pinch zoom first, if necessary) and drag it towards the centre. The rectangle
will get narrower and longer, most probably exceeding screen size at this point. Another use of pinch
zoom can make it fit. Finally, a tap on the <i>X ↔ Y</i> button reverses the image so every third
letter now forms a horizontal line instead of a vertical one and can readily be read.</p>


<h3>Preferences</h3>

<p>The preferences can be used to fine-tune the way splitting text into single letters is done, namely
whether non-alphabetical characters should be ignored or treated as single characters, too. This affects
digits, spaces, punctuation, etc. <i>NB</i> that changing the parsing options generally causes changes
to the alignment as the total effective character count is affected.</p>

<p>These settings are shared with <i>Frequency analysis</i>.</p>
]]></string>

</resources>
