<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">

    <string name="app_name">Puzzlehunt Assistant</string>

    <string name="tVstup">Input:</string>
    <string name="tVystup">Output:</string>
    <string name="tRes">Plaintext:</string>
    <string name="tBsp">Backspace</string>
    <string name="tClear">Clear all</string>
    <string name="tEncode">Encrypt</string>
    <string name="tDecode">Decrypt</string>
    <string name="tCopy">Copy</string>
    <string name="tShare">Share</string>
    <string name="tCtxCopy">Copy</string>
    <string name="tCtxPaste">Paste</string>
    <string name="tRef">Reference</string>
    <string name="tVar">Variants</string>
    <string name="tClose">Close</string>
    <string name="tGo">Go</string>


    <string name="patCopyCap">Text: \"%s\"</string>
    <string name="patBitmapCap">Bitmap: %1$d × %2$d, %3$d B</string>
    <string name="tmpBitmapName" translatable="false">export.png</string>
    <string name="tNotFound">Not found!</string>
    <string name="icon">icon</string>

    <string name="cptMain">Puzzlehunt Assistant</string>
    <string name="cptLicence">Licence Terms</string>

    <string name="tSettings">Settings</string>
    <string name="tHelp">Help</string>
    <string name="tAbout">About…</string>
    <string name="tNews">Release notes</string>
    <string name="tLicence">License</string>

    <string name="tErrCopy">No text copied</string>
    <string name="tErrPaste">Clipboard is empty</string>
    <string name="tErrEncode">Some characters were not recognized and were omitted.</string>
    <string name="tErrVar">Please enter the input first.</string>

    <string name="tSipkaL" translatable="false">◀</string>
    <string name="tSipkaP" translatable="false">▶</string>
    <string name="tSipkaN" translatable="false">▲</string>
    <string name="tSipkaD" translatable="false">▼</string>


<string name="tHelpMain" tools:ignore="Typos"><![CDATA[
<h1>Puzzlehunt Assistant</h1>

<p>The purpose of this application is to help with routine tasks used in cipher solving and
puzzlehunts. Thanks to simple input of the ciphertext, automated translation and many variants
of the solution shown at once, it leaves more time for your own thinking and invention. 
Please note that this app is not meant to, and will not, represent any attempt at artificial
intelligence and provide suggestions on <i>how</i> to solve a problem, but can be of great help
of doing the hard work once you figure out the trick.</p>

<p>Since version 2.0, Puzzlehunt Assistant also offers the reverse – encryption of a plain text
using a number of well-known ciphers. Again, only the sole translation is usually provided by
the respective tools, leaving a potential further obfuscation up to the author.</p>


<h3>Basic usage</h3>

<p>The functions provided by the app are divided into a set of mutually independent components,
each of which deals with a specific kind of ciphers. The components are stand-alone and usually
stateless. To transfer data between components, the Android clipboard can easily be used (see
below).</p>  

<p>Most of the components provide several different actions – decryption, encryption, reference
tables etc. These actions are represented by a set of tabs in the lower row of your screen.
The tabs can be switched by a fling or a tap.</p>

<p>The <i>Back</i> button returns to a previously opened tab or the main menu. Some transitions
(e.g. <i>Encrypt</i> → <i>Decrypt</i> induce a transfer of text entered in the tab being closed
even when using the <i>Back</i> button. However, passive tabs like <i>Reference</i> never alter
or lose your previously entered data.</p>

<p>Each of the components has a separate specific Help topic which can be opened just like this,
using action bar or the the <i>Menu</i> button (Android 2.3 – Gingerbread).
The menu / action bar also links to the Preferences screen for the active component where
there is one. All the settings can also be reached from the main screen.</p>

<p>The recycle bin action button, or the <i>Clear all</i> menu item, re-initializes the component:
any input and user-made changes are reverted to their state when the component was opened.
Finally, the menu provides shortcuts to Copy and Paste commands.</p> 

<p>Any obtained piece of plaintext or list entry can also be copied by clicking it (a menu
appears which also offers sharing the text with another app). Where a problems results into
the generation of a picture, this can be shared with another app or saved in PNG format the
same way.</p>


<h3>Preferences</h3>

<p>All the app preferences are reachable from the main screen (using <i>Menu</i> or the action bar)
or from the individual components. The settings are kept between app restarts. Some of the
preference groups are general, affecting more than one component at a time. This is the case
for preferences which deal with various alphabet tweaks as this is usually specific to the game
as a whole and should be respected by all components indifferently. The defaults are 26-letter
plain English alphabet for all purposes.</p>

<p>Some of the encryption techniques display minor differences with the locale (currently English
and Czech locales are supported). If English is not your preferred locale, you can override the
system default in the overall preferences. Note that all labels and messages will also be affected.</p>


<h3>Tips and tricks</h3>

<h5>Multi-stage processing</h5>

<p>If you wish to feed the result of one component to another, e.g., perform a frequency analysis
of a text you obtained by decoding some Morse code, you can readily use the system clipboard.
Each <i>Plaintext</i> field, as well as every line in a list where multiple variants are shown,
provides a shortcut to copying its contents via a quick context menu. A <i>Copy</i> command
is also available in the menu in most cases. Pasting the copied text into a different component
is equally simple; moreover, in text fields, standard Android paste can be used.</p>

<h5>Second-level tools</h5>

<p>For the sake of compactness and logical consistency, multiple tools are often grouped under a
more general header where they may not seem perfectly intuitive to look for at first sight. Try
looking for a <i>Multi-tap</i>, <i>Bifid</i>, and <i>Trifid</i> ciphers under <i>Grid Ciphers</i>
and for <i>1:1 substitution</i> under <i>Frequency Analysis</i>.</p>

<h5>Small displays</h5>

<p>The app has been designed with displays of many sizes in mind. Sometimes the amount of information
is just too large for the small screen of a smartphone. Often scrolling is inevitable to reach all
the window contents. If the buttons seem to be too small to be used with ease, try orienting your
screen in landscape. If the soft keyboard seems to cover some important part of the screen, it can
be hidden using the <i>Back</i> button.</p>


<h3>Disclaimer</h3>

<p>Even though much care has been put into compiling the often encountered variants, reference tables
and word lists, these can never be considered perfect, complete and/or infallible as all the work has
been done by a single enthusiast programmer. The sources for marginal or specialized uses of Morse
code or Braille have been compiled from multiple sources and may be inexact, or defined differently
in your country. If in some doubt, please always double check the solutions presented to you by the
app. (In case you find some inconsistencies please contact the author, see below.)</p>


<h3>Like the app? Have something to say?</h3>

<p>Do you appreciate help the Puzzlehunt Assistant has given? Care to give some help back? I always
deeply appreciate thorough tests of the app, its behaviour in unpredicted situations, notices of errors
or petty annoying behaviour, or just general enhancement ideas (respecting the overall concept of the
app). Rating and comments in Google Play are also most welcome. If you were willing to offer a more
involving help like translation into a new language (or corrections of my English, for that matter),
please do not hesitate to write to the author personally at <tt>vasek.potocek@gmail.com</tt>.</p>

<p>This is an Open Source software project (see License). You can find the source code at:<br/>
<tt>https://github.com/vasekp/sifry</tt></p>
]]></string>


<string name="patAbout"><![CDATA[
<h5>Puzzlehunt Assistant</h5>

<p>Version %s</p>

<p>© 2012-2018 Vašek Potoček</p>

<p>Special thanks to testers:<br/>
– Martin Polívka<br/>
– Vítězslav Plachý<br/>
– Michal Přibyl</p>
]]></string>


<string name="patNewVersion"><![CDATA[
<h5><i>Welcome to version %s!</i></h5>

<p>The <i>Dictionary Search</i> data are now a part of the application package. If you
have been experiencing problems downloading the external file, you can now explore the
component directly.</p>
]]></string>


    <string name="tLicDict">English word list (from aspell-en v7.1)</string>

    <string-array name="saLicence" translatable="false">
        <item>%1$s v%2$s</item>
        <item>svg-android v1.1</item>
        <item>PCRE library v8.31</item>
        <item>%s</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="iaLicence" translatable="false">
        <item>@raw/lic_sifry</item>
        <item>@raw/lic_svg</item>
        <item>@raw/lic_pcre</item>
        <item>@raw/lic_dict</item>
    </array>
	
	
<string name="tHelpNews"><![CDATA[
<h1>Changes in v2.2</h1>

– Minimum Android version bumped to 4.0.1 (Ice Cream Sandwich)<br/>
– Morse transmission and file export no longer supported (app no more requires any extra permissions)<br/>
– ARM64 devices now supported<br/>
– Bug fixes<br/>

<h3>Older versions</h3>

<h5>Version 2.1 (28 Sep 2015)</h5>
– Dictionary data packed in the main application APK<br/>
– Android 2.2 and older no longer supported<br/>

<h5>Version 2.0 (21 Jan 2014)</h5>
– Help available for all tools<br/>
– Enciphering available besides deciphering<br/>
– Language selection (English / Czech)<br/>
– New preference system<br/>
– Redesigned user interface<br/>
– New component: <i>Transposition ciphers</i><br/>
– <i>Morse Code</i>: transmit using flashlight or speaker<br/>
– <i>Braille</i>: better recognition of the standard, formatting support<br/>
– <i>Substitution Ciphers</i>: many new cipher types<br/>
– <i>Frequency Analysis</i>: new statistics, Empirical Substitution<br/>
– <i>Calendar</i>: more calendar information, extended possibilities<br/>
– <i>Checkpoint Logbook</i>: export<br/>
– Better mirror for downloading dictionary data<br/>
– Error fixes<br/>

<h5>Version 1.3 (6 Dec 2012)</h5>
– Extended and reorganized Preferences<br/>
– English localization (trial run)<br/>
– <i>Braille</i>: allowed parsing digits, punctuation, abbreviations<br/>
– <i>Semaphore</i>: flag thumbnails, allowed parsing digits<br/>

<h5>Version 1.2 (1 Dec 2012)</h5>
– Main Menu icons replaced by scalable vector graphics<br/>
– Further accommodation to large and small screens<br/>
– <i>Letter Numbers</i>: column headings in Reference<br/>
– <i>Pigpen Ciphers</i>: new pigpen variants<br/>
– <i>Frequency Analysis</i>: new character statistics<br/>

<h5>Version 1.1 (28 Nov 2012)</h5>
– Android 1.6 support<br/>
– Better layout for large and small screens<br/>
– <i>Dictionary Search</i>: allowed using internal storage if external is unreachable<br/>
– <i>Letter Numbers</i>: reference table including ASCII and permutation indexing<br/>
]]></string>


</resources>
