<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="cptZapisnik">Checkpoint Logbook</string>
    <string name="tZNew">Add checkpoint…</string>
    <string name="tZPozn">…</string>
    <string name="tZClearQ">Delete all entries?</string>

    <string name="tZOdchod">Check out</string>
    <string name="tZZmena">Modify</string>
    <string name="tZSmaz">Delete</string>

    <string name="cptZDAdd">Add record</string>
    <string name="cptZDModify">Edit record</string>
    <string name="tZDNazev">Checkpoint title:</string>
    <string name="tZDHeslo">Checkpoint code:</string>
    <string name="tZDRes">Result:</string>
    <string name="tZDUpres">Specification:</string>
    <string name="tZDPozn">Remark:</string>
    <string name="patZDDefault">Checkpoint %d</string>
    <string name="tZDZobr">Display</string>
    <string name="tZDPrichod">Check-in time:</string>
    <string name="tZDOdchod">Check-out time:</string>

	
<string name="tHelpZapisnik"><![CDATA[
<h1>Checkpoint Logbook</h1>

<p>You can use this component to log the arrivals, departures, solution etc. in multi–level
puzzlehunt games. All the contents of the logbook are saved between sessions.</p>


<h3>Basic usage</h3>

<p>When approaching a new checkpoint, or entering a new level of a puzzlehunt, click <i>Add
checkpoint</i>. This opens a dialog with pre-filled arrival time and a checkpoint name, defaulting
to \"Checkpoint\" and a ordinal number. Of course, the pre-filled fields can be edited just like
any other ones.</p>

<p>When a puzzle is finished, you can record the time of departure clicking the last added
item in the checkpoint list. A slightly different dialog appears, now allowing to record the
solution of the puzzle and optional comments along with the departure time.</p>

<p>A previously closed checkpoint can also be revisited to review or change any piece of data
associated with it. The full dialog comprises both the arrival- and departure-related fields
together. <i>NB</i> that it is also possible to reveal the full version of the dialog at
arrival using the <i>Unfold</i> button.</p>


<h3>Preferences</h3>

<p>In the component settings, you can enable or disable the automatic numbering of checkpoints as
\"Checkpoint 1, 2, …\". If the automatic numbering is disabled, newly opened checkpoints will have
no pre-filled name. Even if it is enabled, the pre-filled name can be edited, e.g., to reflect
irregularities in the numbering like \"1A\", \"1B\". When determining the name for a new checkpoint,
the app will look for the first empty slot following the prescribed pattern.</p>


<h3>Tips and tricks</h3>

<p>If you fill in <i>Specification</i> or <i>Remark</i> in the checkpoint details, a \"…\" sign will
appear next to it in the main list. This is a quick indication that there is further information
available which is not readily visible in the overview.</p>
]]></string>

</resources>
