<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="cptKalendar">Calendar</string>
    <string name="tKDMesicRok">Month, year:</string>
    <string name="tKDDny">Calendar:</string>
    <string name="tKDDenRoku">Day of year:</string>
    <string name="patKDDniOd">Days since %s:</string>
    <string name="tKDJmeno">Name:</string>

    <string name="tKDDef">Calendar</string>
    <string name="tKDRefJD">Name → Date</string>
    <string name="tKDRefDJ">Date → Name</string>

	
<string name="tHelpKalendar"><![CDATA[
<h1>Calendar</h1>

<p>Use this component to navigate in the calendar, using various combinations of data (month
number, day of month, day of year, weekday etc.) and retrieving the full set of such values
for each day. You can also use it to compute the differences between two dates in nnumber of
days easily.</p>


<h3>Basic usage</h3>

<p>The calendar displayed in the main part of the screen is initially set to the current date.
Changing any of the text fields or clicking a day in the calendar widget will select the new
date and recompute all the remaining fields accordingly. Month and year can also be more
conveniently changed using the arrow buttons, or swiping over the calendar widget vertically.</p>


<h3>Advanced usage</h3>

<p>The <i>Days since</i> field displays (or allows the user to enter) the difference in days with
respect to the current system date. This anchor can be changed by double clicking the requested
date in the calendar widget. It will be shown in red to reflect this property.</p>

<p>It is also possible to mark a subset of days in the calendar by long-clicking them. The marked
days will be displayed in yellow colour. This has no other purpose than checking for a possible
geometrical pattern leading to the solution of a calendar-based puzzle.</p>

<p>Neither the anchor date nor the set of dates marked this way are kept when the component is
exited.</p>


<h3>Name days</h3>

<p>The app contains a database of Czech and Slovak name days, i.e., names associated with most
of the days in a year. This feature is hidden in the English locale by default but can be brought
up via Preferences.</p>

<p>If name days are enabled, the name day associated with the selected day of year (or public
holiday name in the few cases where there is none) is displayed along the other calendar data.
It can also be used to conversely find a day by its name day. If diacritics are present in
the name you would like to enter, they can be omitted.</p>

<p>The layout of the component also changes to offer two new tabs, allowing to browse all
name days either alphabetically or in the order they appear during the year, respectively.</p>  
]]></string>


    <string-array name="saKDKalendare">
        <item>Don\'t display</item>
        <item>Czech</item>
        <item>Slovak</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="saKDKalendareKody">
        <item/>
        <item>svatkyCZ</item>
        <item>svatkySK</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="pref_kal_namedays_default"/>


    <string-array name="saKDMesice">
        <item>January</item>
        <item>February</item>
        <item>March</item>
        <item>April</item>
        <item>May</item>
        <item>June</item>
        <item>July</item>
        <item>August</item>
        <item>September</item>
        <item>October</item>
        <item>November</item>
        <item>December</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
